Jose García Profile

LOCATION

Medellín, Colombia

PHONE +57 (305) 357-3300

E-MAIL josepplloo@gmail.com

WEB linkedin.com/in/josem-garciag qithub.com/josepplloo

REFERENCES ANY RUIZ Web Engineer at Huge anruiz@hugeinc.com

OSCAR ORTEGA Professor at UdeA oscar.ortega@udea.edu.co Informatics engineer and student of MSc. in software engineering whit over four years of experience mainly as consultant, backend developer, as well as lecturer and research experience in Software Product Line Engineering and Data Mining.

Education

August 2015 -University of Antioquia - Medellín

2019 MSc in software engineering

February 2006 -JAIME ISAZA CADAVID COLOMBIAN POLYTECHNIC - MEDELLÍN April 2015

Engineer's degree - Informatic Engineer

Skills

English (60%), Spanish (100%). LANGUAGES: Programming CSS, Docker, Git, HTML, Java, JavaScript, JBoss, Maven, Python, LANGUAGES, SOFTWARE

& FRAMEWORKS: Red Hat, SQL, Scrum.

Agile, CI/CD, Hefesto, Software METHODOLOGIES &

PRACTICES: design patterns.

Experience

DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - SUMMAN S.A.S

JULY 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

Developer Engineer: Build, deliver and support Red Hat enterprise solutions for regional customers.

LECTURER – UNIVERSITY OF ANTIQUIA

MARCH 2016 - 2019

Lecturer in Introduction of Systems Engineering.

RESEARCH ENGINEER - ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGIES OF ORGANIZATIONS AND SOCIETY – ITOS & COLCIENCIAS

NOVEMBER 2015 - FEBRUARY 2016

Finding material for a systematic literature review of Product Line Engineering and Data Mining.

DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - SUMMAN S.A.S

JANUARY 2012 - JUNE 2015

Software analyst: Maintain DataVar software, build pipelines on Pentaho for ITIL projects and deliver Red Hat enterprise solutions.

Projects

GUIDE TO INDUSTRY ADOPTION OF SOFTWARE PRODUCT LINES

DECEMBER 2015 - AUGUST 2017

Product catalog or portfolio is a tool to communicate the minimal capacity of production in the product line, the aim in this book chapter was figure out how the main concepts inside this technology can help to construct a minimum viable product.

PRODUCT: Incremental Definition of Product Catalog for a Product Line in Guide to industry adoption of software product lines. https://goo.gl/d29dFt

CONFORMATION, EVOLUTION AND CONSISTENCY BASED ON THE CONCEPT OF PRODUCT LINE IN ORGANIZATIONS AND DATA MINING SOLUTIONS

NOVEMBER 2015 - FEBRUARY 2016

Development of a review for the technics of data mining in order to modeling Product lines.